Guide to the Carol D. Litchfield microbiology collection, 1924-1997
George Mason University Libraries
Special Collections and Archives, George Mason University
Carol D. Litchfield microbiology collection
1924-1997
George Mason University. Special Collections and Archives
Carol D. Litchfield
C0047
16.5 linear feet (11 boxes)
The Carol D. Litchfield microbiology collection contains published reports and government studies as well as a few personal documents and papers encompassing topics such as microbiology of organisms and water quality.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no access restrictions.
Acquisition Information
The collection was first donated by Carol D. Litchfield in 1995 followed by more donations until 2008.
Biographical Information
Microbiologist and biochemist Carol D. Litchfield was born in Cincinnati, Ohio, in 1936. She received a Masters of Science in Microbiology from the University of Cincinnati in 1960 and went on to pursue a Ph.D. in Biochemistry at Texas A and M University. Following a post-doctoral appointment at the University of North Wales, Dr. Litchfield joined the faculty at Rutgers, State University of New Jersey. After ten years at Rutgers, she worked as Head of Environmental Toxicology at Haskell Laboratory, a DuPont laboratory, then as Senior Scientist for its bioremediation subsidiary. Dr. Litchfield then founded her own consulting company and worked for Chester Environmental prior to joining George Mason University in 1993. A member of several professional societies, Litchfield served as the president of the Society for Industrial Microbiology (SIM) from 2007 to 2008. She was awarded the Charles Porter Award in 2012 from the organization for her achievements in applied microbiology and her exceptional service to SIM. She died in 2012.
Scope and Content
The Carol D. Litchfield microbiology collection contains journal publications, government studies, microfiche, and research data, both published and personal. This collection features many different areas of microbiology, ranging from research methods and analysis to water quality data influencing policy making. Some highlights in this collection contain the New York Bight Project, which deals with water quality, sludge, and sewage dumping in the New York Bight, the waters between New York and New Jersey. Also within this collection are government manuals, findings, and reports on microbiology, as well as some personal field work, research, and papers by Dr. Litchfield. A few pieces of the collection are in French, German, and Japanese. The majority of this collection dates from the mid-1970s to the end of the 1980s, and the majority of the material contains information on the New York Bight project and other water quality studies and reports.
Arrangement
There is some arrangement by topic and geographical location.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Related Material
The George Mason University Special Collections and Archives also holds other collections for research in related scientific fields in the,, and the.
Index Terms
Persons:
Litchfield, Carol D.
Corporate Names:
American Petroleum Institute.; Association of Ground Water Scientists and Engineers (U.S.); Marine EcoSystems Analysis Program.; United States. Environmental Protection Agency.; United States. National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration.; United States. National Technical Information Service.
Geographical Names:
New York Bight (N.J. and N.Y.)
Subjects:
Limnology.; Sewage disposal in the ocean.; Waste disposal in the ocean.; Water--Microbiology.
Contents List
- Carol D. Litchfield Microbiology collection, 1924-1997
  This collection contains over 300 documents of reports, papers, and manuals in microbiology, oceanography, and limnology.
  - Environmental Impact Statement on the Ocean Dumping of Sewage Sludge in the New York Bight Final, September 1978 (Box 1, Volume 1)
    U.S. Environmental Protection Agency Region II, Approved by Eckardt C. Beck - Regional Administrator
    Final results of the reexamination of the environmental impact statement (EIS) of the existing dump site
  - Ocean Dumping in the New York Bight NOAA Technical Report ERL 321-MESA 2, March 1975 (Box 1, Volume 2)
    NOAA, Robert M. White, Administrator; ERL, Wilmot N. Hess, Director
    Overview of the dumping situation in the New York Bight and aspects of it
  - The New York Bight Project - 1975 Stony Brook, Long Island New York, March 1975 (Box 1, Volume 3)
    U.S. DOC, Elliot Richardson, Secretary; NOAA, Robert M. White, Administrator; ERL Wilmont Hess, Director
    MESA program and the MESA New York Bight Project
  - Long Island Beach Pollution: June 1976, February 1977 (Box 1, Volume 4)
    R. Lawrence Swanson, Gerald M. Hansler, Lt. Comdr. Joseph Marotta
    MESA Special Report
  - MESA New York Bight Project Annual Report for Fiscal Year 1977, October 1978 (Box 1, Volume 5)
    MESA, NOAA, U.S. DOC, EPA
    Annual report for fiscal year 1977 presents an overview of MESA New York Bight Project activities between October 1, 1976 and September 30, 1977.
  - Final Report Part 1 The Abundances, Distribution, and Flux of Nutrients and Chlorophyll A in the New York Bight Apex, February 1976 (Box 1, Volume 6)
    I.W. Duedall, H.B. O'Connors, J. G. Parker, R.W. Wilson and A. S. Robbins
    Tidal, spatial, and seasonal changes in salinity, temperature and concentration levels between Sandy Hook, NJ and Rockaway Point, NY between November 1973 and June 1974
  - Ocean Dumping in the New York Bight Since 1973, April 1974 (Box 1, Volume 7)
    EPA Region II Surveillance and Analysis Division
    Briefing Report; Practices and permits for sludge dumping.
  - Dispersion of Sewage Sludge Discharged into the New York Bight, December 1974 (Box 1, Volume 8)
    A. M. Teeter, R. J. Callaway, D. W. Denbo
    EPA-600/3-78-086a; stamped as WITHDRAWN
  - Dispersion of Sewage Sludge Discharged into the New York Bight, 1975 (Box 1, Volume 9)
    A.M. Teeter, R.J. Callaway, G.R. Ditsworth, D.W. Denbo, D. Browne
    EPA-600/3-78-086b; stamped as WITHDRAWN
  - Draft Environmental Impact Statement (EIS) for New York Bight Acid Waste Disposal Site Designation, November 1979 (Box 1, Volume 10)
    T.A. Wastler
    Administrative/Regulatory action - The proposed action is the designation of the New York Bight Acid Waste Disposal Site for continuing use
  - Phase 1 Report of Technical Alternatives to Ocean Disposal of Sludge in the New York City-New Jersey Metropolitan Area, June 1975 (Box 1, Volume 11)
    Camp Dresser and McKee, Alexander Potter Associates
    Alternatives to Ocean Dumping
  - Distribution and Abundance of Benthic Macrofauna in the Sewage Sludge Disposal Area, New York Bight Apex, February 1975, November 1977 (Box 1, Volume 12)
    John Pearce, Janice Caracciolo, Martha Halsey, Leslie Rogers
    Impact of ocean waste disposal on the ecosystem of the New York Bight apex since 1968; NOAA Data Report ERL MESA-36
  - MESA New York Bight Project Expanded Water Column Characterization Cruise (XWCC 14) NOAA Ship George B. Kelez, June - July 1977, February 1978 (Box 1, Volume 13)
    John B. Hazelworth, Terren M. Niedrauer, Philip G. Hanson
    Report presents the corrected physical and chemical (nutrient) data from this cruise; NOAA Data Report ERL MESA-37
  - Hydrographic Data from New York Bight: July - November 1976, January 1978 (Box 1, Volume 14)
    Frank Steimle
    Collection of data investigating oxygen depletion in the sub-thermocline water layer off New Jersey; NOAA Data Report ERL MESA-35
  - MESA New York Bight Project Expanded Water Column Characterization Cruise (XWCC 9) NOAA Ship George B. Kelez, May 1976 (Box 1, Volume 15)
    John B. Hazelworth, Robert B. Start, Shailer R. Cummings, George A. Berberian
    Data collected for analysis of the water characteristics and movement; NOAA Data Report ERL MESA-31
  - New York Bight Project Annual Report for FY 1976-76T, December 1977 (Box 1, Volume 16)
    NOAA, U.S. DOC
    July 1, 1975 to September 30, 1976; NOAA Technical Memorandum ERL MESA-25
  - Environmental Impact Statement (EIS) for 106-Mile Ocean Waste Disposal Site Designation, February 1980 (Box 1, Volume 17)
    U.S. EPA Oil and Special Materials Control Division
    Final report, Administrative/Regulatory action
  - Ocean Dumping in the New York Bight Facts and Figures, July 1973 (Box 1, Volume 18)
    U.S. EPA Region II Surveillance and Analysis Division
    Facts and Figures of Waste Discharges in the New York - New Jersey Metropolitan Area
  - Ocean Disposal in the New York Bight Technical Briefing Report Number 1, July 1974 (Box 1, Volume 19)
    2 Copies; Volume of Waste Materials - 1973, Long-Range Plan for Phase Out, Technical Findings
  - Ocean Disposal in the New York Bight Technical Briefing Report Number 2, April 1975 (Box 1, Volume 20)
    2 Copies; Volumes and Characteristics of Waste Materials Dumped, Long Term Goals for Phase Out of Ocean Disposal in the New York Bight, Technical Findings
  - New York Bight Project Project Development Plan and Technical Development Plan, April 1977 (Box 1, Volume 21)
    U.S. DOC, NOAA, ERL, MESA, and New York Bight Project Office
    Purpose of the program and overall goals, research and management plan
  - Winter Conditions in the New York Bight 1973-1974, September 1974 (Box 1, Volume 22)
    Grumman Ecosystems Corporation and Quirk, Lawler, and Matusky, Engineers
    PB-245 191, First Report
  - MESA New York Bight Project Expanded Water Column Characterization Cruise (XWCC 9) NOAA Ship George B. Kelez, May 1976, 1977 (Box 1, Volume 23)
    J.B. Hazelworth
    Microfiche, 1-2 of 2, NOAA DR ERL MESA-31
  - MESA New York Bight Project Expanded Water Column Characterization Cruise (XWCC 10) NOAA Ship George B. Kelez, 28 June - 1 July, 1976, 1977 (Box 1, Volume 24)
    R.B. Starr
    Microfiche, 1 of 1, NOAA DR ERL MESA-28
  - MESA New York Bight Project Expanded Water Column Characterization Cruise (XWCC 11) NOAA Ship Researcher, September 1976, 1977 (Box 1, Volume 25)
    Microfiche, 1-3 of 3, NOAA DR ERL MESA-29
  - MESA New York Bight Project Expanded Water Column Characterization Cruise (XWCC 13) NOAA Ship George B. Kelez, May - June 1977 (Box 1, Volume 26)
    Microfiche, 1-3 of 3, NOAA DR ERL MESA-34
  - MESA New York Bight Project Expanded Water Column Characterization Cruise (XWCC 14) NOAA Ship George B. Kelez, June - July 1977, 1978 (Box 1, Volume 27)
    Microfiche, 1-2 of 2, NOAA DR ERL MESA-37
  - MESA New York Bight Project Expanded Water Column Characterization Cruise (XWCC 15) NOAA Ship George B. Kelez, August 1977, 1978 (Box 1, Volume 28)
    Microfiche, 1-3 of 3, NOAA DR ERL MESA-38
  - MESA New York Bight Project Expanded Water Column Characterization Cruise (XWCC 16) NOAA Ship George B. Kelez, October 1977, 1978 (Box 1, Volume 29)
    Microfiche, 1-2 of 2, NOAA DR ERL MEA-39
  - MESA New York Bight Project Trace Metal Data: Expanded Water Column Characterization Cruises (XWCC-12, 13, 15 ,16) NOAA Ship George B. Kelez, 1977, 1982 (Box 1, Volume 30)
    NOAA
    Microfiche, 1 of 1, REQ. #42125, NOAA DR OMPA-12
  - MESA New York Bight Project Water Column Characterization Cruise NOAA Ship George B. Kelez, 1978 (Box 1, Volume 31)
    Microfiche, 1-2 of 2, NOAA DR ERL MESA-33
  - New York Bight Project, Water Column Sampling Cruises #9-12 of the NOAA Ship Ferrel, May 1975 (Box 1, Volume 32)
    John B. Hazelworth, Bryon L. Kolitz, Robert B. Starr, Robert L. Charnell, George A. Berberian, Maxine A. Weiselberg
    Microfiche, 1-3 of 3; NOAA Data Report ERL MESA-3
  - New York Bight Project, Water Column Sampling Cruises #6-8 of the NOAA Ship Ferrel, January 1975 (Box 1, Volume 33)
    Microfiche, 1-2 of 2; NOAA DR MESA-1
  - Water Movement Within the Apex of the New York Bight During Summer and Fall of 1973, April 1975 (Box 1, Volume 34)
    Robert L. Charnell, Dennis A. Mayer
    Microfiche, 1 of 1, NOAA TM ERL MESA-3
  - Assessment of Offshore Dumping in the New York Bight, Technical Background: Physical Oceanography, Geological Oceanography, Chemical Oceanography, April 1975 (Box 1, Volume 35)
    Robert L. Charnell
    Microfiche, 1 of 1, NOAA TR ERL 332-MESA 3
  - Assessment of Offshore Dumping; Technical Background: Physical Oceanography, Geological Oceanography, Chemical Oceanography, April 1975 (Box 1, Volume 36)
    Microfiche, 1 of 1, NOAA TM ERL MESA-1
  - Annual Summary of Research Results for Fiscal Year 1974 (Box 1, Volume 37)
    New York Bight Project
    Microfiche, 1-3 of 3, NOAA TM ERL MESA-2
  - Suspended Particulate Matter in the New York Bight Apex: September-November 1973, 1974 (Box 1, Volume 38)
    David E. Drake
    Microfiche, 1 of 1, NOAA TR ERL 318-MESA 1
  - A Study of the Sources, Transport, and Reaction of Suspended Particles in Waters of the New York Bight, 1978 (Box 1, Volume 39)
    P.R. Betzer
    Microfiche, 1 of 1, NOAA TM ERL MESA-23
  - The 1973 Bathymetric Survey in the New York Bight Apex: Maps and Geological Implications, 1977 (Box 1, Volume 40)
    G.L. Freeland and G.F. Merrill
    Microfiche, 1 of 1, NOAA TM ERL MESA-19
  - Distribution and Abundance of Benthic Organisms in the New York Bight Apex, Five Seasonal Cruises, August 1973 - September 1974., 1977 (Box 1, Volume 41)
    J. Pearce
    Microfiche, 1-9 of 9, NOAA DATA REPORT ERL MESA-32
  - Distribution and Abundance of Benthic Microfauna in the Sewage Sludge Disposal Area, N.Y. Bight Apex, February 1975, 1977 (Box 1, Volume 42)
    Microfiche, 1 of 1, NOAA DR ERL MESA-36
  - Field Measurements of the Bottom Frictional Boundary Layer in the New York Bight, 1978 (Box 1, Volume 43)
    Barry M. Lesht
    Microfiche, 1-2 of 2, NOAA TM ERL MESA-28
  - Bottom Friction Under Waves in the Presence of a Weak Current., 1978 (Box 1, Volume 44)
    W.D. Grant and O.S. Madsen
    Microfiche, 1-2 of 2, NOAA TM ERL MESA-29
  - New York Bight Annual Report for FY 1976-76T., 1977 (Box 1, Volume 45)
    Microfiche, 1-2 of 2, NOAA TM ERL MESA-25
  - Hydrographic Data from New York Bight: July-November 1976, 1978 (Box 1, Volume 46)
    Microfiche, 1-3 of 3, NOAA DR ERL MESA-35
  - The Ocean Dumping Quandary Waste Disposal in the New York Bight, 1983 (Box 1, Volume 47)
    Donald F. Squires
    Book
  - SINC Compendium Report, "Benthic and Planktonic Bacteria", 1982 (Box 1, Volume 48)
    Carol D. Litchfield
    Letter by Dr. Litchfield to Dr. Mayer with attached SINC Compendium Report entitled "Benthic and Planktonic Bacteria" included with Dr. Mayer's reply
  - The Proceedings of the New York Bight Dredged Material Disposal Alternatives Workshop, October 1977 (Box 1, Volume 49)
    Sponsored by U.S. Army Corps of Engineers NY District
    Proceedings of the three day workshop
  - NOAA's New York Bight Marine Ecosystems Analysis Project: An Interdisciplinary Study of the Marine Environment, October - November 1974 (Box 1, Volume 50)
    Allan Hirsch
    Reprinted from Marine Technology Society Journal Vol. 8 No. 9
  - Beach Forms and Coastal Processes, January 1975 (Box 1, Volume 51)
    Warren E. Yasso and Elliott M. Hartman Jr.
    MESA New York Bight Atlas Monograph 11
  - Demographic Patterns., June 1975 (Box 1, Volume 52)
    Charles T. Koebel and Donald A. Krueckeberg
    MESA New York Bight Atlas Monograph 23
  - Abstracts Special Symposium The Middle Atlantic Continental Shelf and New York Bight, November 1975 (Box 1, Volume 53)
    Co-sponsored by: American Society of Limnology and Oceanography, Chesapeake Bay Institution, The Johns Hopkins University, MESA, New York Bight Project, NOAA, New York Sea Grant Institute
    Abstracts
  - A Geochemical and Sedimentological Study of the Dredged Material Deposit in the New York Bight, February 1981 (Box 1, Volume 54)
    R. Dayal, M.G. Heaton, M. Fuhrmann, T.W. Duedall
    NOAA Technical Memorandum OMPA-3
  - Distribution and Abundance of Benthic Organisms in the New York - New Jersey Outer Continental Shelf, December 1977 (Box 1, Volume 55)
    NOAA Data Report ERL MESA-30
  - Oxygen Depletion and Associated Benthic Moralities in New York Bight, 1976, December 1979 (Box 1, Volume 56)
    Editors: R. Lawrence Swanson, Carl J. Sindermann
    NOAA Professional Paper 11
  - Analysis of Residual Chlorinated Hydrocarbons, Aromatic Hydrocarbons and Related Compounds in Selected Sources, Sinks, and Biota of the New York Bight, May 1981 (Box 1, Volume 57)
    William D. MacLeod, Jr., L. Scott Ramos, Andrew J. Friedman, Douglas G. Burrows, Patty G. Prohaska, David L. Fisher, Donald W. Brown
    NOAA Technical Memorandum OMPA-6
  - Microbial Contributions to Organic Mineralization in the Waters and Sediments of the New York Bight, August 1979 (Box 1, Volume 58)
    2 Copies; Final Report for 1977-1978 NOAA-MESA - New York Bight Studies Grant No. 04-07-022-44013
  - The Seasonal Maxima of 'Ceratium tripos' with Particular Reference to a Major New York Bight Bloom, June 1978 (Box 1, Volume 59)
    John B. Mahoney
    2 Copies; Technical Series Report No. 16, PB-278 914
  - Oxygen Depletion and Associated Environmental Disturbances in the Middle Atlantic Bight in 1976 A Report Series on a Series of Interagency Workshops Held in November and December 1976, February 1977 (Box 2, Volume 1)
    U.S. DOC, NTIS
    Bound report and on the spine - "The Anoxic Episode Workshop Final Report"; PB-287 956
  - Final Report on the IN SITU Bioremediation at the Victoria West Landfill, 1990 (Box 2, Volume 2)
    Report prepared by: Carol D. Litchfield, Approved by: David L. Wickersham
    Archival folder; Includes a 34 pg executive summary with background and description of the experiment and three floppy disks of data
  - Effects of Toxicants on Plankton, 1982 (Box 2, Volume 3)
    Gerald E. Walsh
    Presented at the International Course on Environmental Toxicology, August 1982, at Heriot-Watt University in Edinburgh, Scotland.
  - Abstracts: Third International Symposium on Microbial Ecology, August 1983, Michigan State University (Box 2, Volume 4)
    ASM
    Section 1: Invited papers, Section 2: Contributed papers
  - Evaluation of an Automatic Technique for Counting Unicellular Organisms, 1962 (Box 2, Volume 5)
    Sayed Z. El-Sayed
    Final Report, Research Conducted Through the Texas A and M Research Foundation
  - A Guide to Air Quality Monitoring with Lichens, 1973 (Box 2, Volume 6)
    William C. Denison
    A guide in understanding and the ability to identify lichens and air quality at one or more sites
  - Symposium on the Recovery of Indicator Organisms Employing Membrane. Filters, September 1977 (Box 2, Volume 7)
    Edited by: Robert H. Bordner, Clifford F. Frith, and John A. Winter
    Book, EPA-600/9-77-024
  - Technical Support Services for Superfund Site Remediation, Interim Directory, February 1990 (Box 2, Volume 8)
    EPA, Office of Solid Waste and Emergency Response
    Directory, EPA/540/8-90/001
  - Engineered Organisms in the Environment, 5-8 April 1988 (Box 2, Volume 9)
    Dr. Bernard Dixon
    A 'lay summary' based on the FIRST INTERNATIONAL CONFERENCE ON THE RELEASE OF GENETICALLY ENGINEERED MICROORGANISMS (REGEM 1) held in Cardiff, UK
  - Laboratory Methods in Anaerobic Bacteriology, 1977 (Box 2, Volume 10)
    V.R. Dowell, Jr. and T.M. Hawkins
    CDC Laboratory Manual
  - Anaerobe Laboratory Manual, 1972 (Box 2, Volume 11)
    The Staff of the Anaerobe Laboratory Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
    Manual
  - Computers in Clinical Microbiology, 1985 (Box 2, Volume 12)
    Manual; Manual prepared for training not designed as a computer manual for the diagnostic laboratory and should not be used as such.
  - Review and Evaluation of Available Techniques for Determining Persistence and Routes of Degradation of Chemical Substances in the Environment, May 1975 (Box 2, Volume 13)
    P.H. Howard, J. Sexena, P.R. Durkin, L.-T. Ou
    Final Report
  - Population Genetics of Bacteria, 1995 (Box 2, Volume 14)
    Edited by: S. Baumberg, J.P.W. Young, E.M.H. Wellington, and J.R. Saunders
    Fifty-Second Symposium of the Society for General Microbiology Held at the University of Leicester January 1995
  - Impact of the Use of Microorganisms on the Aquatic Environment, January 1975 (Box 2, Volume 15)
    Edited by: Al W. Bourquin, Donald G. Ahearn, and Samuel P. Meyers
    Contains the proceedings of a symposium-workshop sponsored by the EPA Gulf Breeze Environmental Research Laboratory to determine the possible impact of artificially introducing microbial insect control agents or oil-degrading agents into the aquatic environment
  - The Quantitative Relation between Rate of Photosynthesis and Chlorophyll Content in Chlorella pyrenoidosa, 1938 (Box 2, Volume 16)
    J.C. Van Hille
    Book written in German
  - The Background to Eduard Buchner's Discovery of Cell-Free Fermentation, 1971 (Box 2, Volume 17)
    Robert Kohler
    Journal of the History of Biology, stapled booklet
  - The Jubilee Medallion as an Emblem of the American Society for Microbiology, May 1974 (Box 2, Volume 18)
    ASM News
    Article from ASM New Vol.40, No.5, May 1974; in clear plastic folder
  - Federation Proceedings, August 1976 (Box 2, Volume 19)
    Publisher: Charles C. Thomas
    Volume 35, Number 10
  - Microbial Applications, 1969 (Box 2, Volume 20)
    Harold J. Benson
    A Laboratory Manual in General Microbiology, 2nd Edition, spiral bound
  - A Manual for Pathogenic Bacteriology, 1953 (Box 2, Volume 21)
    Henrik J. Stafseth, John P. Newman, Jack J. Stockton
    Laboratory manual, spiral bound
  - Proceedings of the Society for General Microbiology, May 1976 (Box 2, Volume 22)
    Society for General Microbiology
    Vol. III Part 3
  - Systems for Sterilization of Culture Media, 1977 (Box 2, Volume 23)
    Millipore
    Guide for media sterilization
  - Observations of Bioluminescent Bacteria in Continuous Culture, 1975 (Box 2, Volume 24)
    Lynda Arlene Kiefer
    A thesis submitted to the Faculty of Biology, Gamma College, The University of West Florida in partial fulfillment of the requirements for the degree of Masters of Science
  - Invertebrate Identification Manual, 1967 (Box 2, Volume 25)
    Richard A. Pimentel
    Identification manual
  - Effects of Several Metals on Smolting of Coho Salmon., September 1978 (Box 2, Volume 26)
    Harold W. Lorz, Ronald H. Williams, Charles A. Fustish
    Government report, EPA-600/3-78-090
  - Effects of Copper and Zinc on Smoltification of Coho Salmon, March 1977 (Box 2, Volume 27)
    Harold W. Lorz, Barry P. McPherson
    2 copies, Government report, EPA-600/3-77-032
  - Effects of Selected Herbicides on Smolting of Coho Salmon, June 1979 (Box 2, Volume 28)
    Harold W. Lorz, Susan W. Glenn, Ronald H. Williams, Clair M. Kunkel, Logan A. Norris, Bobby R. Loper
    Government report, EPA-600/3-79-071
  - A Guide for the Recognition of Some Disease Conditions and Abnormalities in Marine Fish, March 1978 (Box 2, Volume 29)
    Carl J. Sinderman, John J. Ziskowski, Valentine T. Anderson Jr.
    Technical Series Report No. 14, Sandy Hook Laboratory
  - Laboratory and Field Investigations in Marine Biology, 1974 (Box 2, Volume 30)
    James L. Sumich, Gordon H. Dudley
    Laboratory manual
  - Bulletin of the Faculty of Fisheries Hokkaido University, 1974 - 1975 (Box 3, Volume 1)
    Faculty of Fisheries, Hokkaido University, Hakodate, Japan
    Vol. 25, Written in Japanese and English
  - Bulletin of the Faculty of Fisheries Hokkaido University, June 1975 (Box 3, Volume 2)
    Vol. 26 No. 1, Written in Japanese and English
  - Bulletin of the Faculty of Fisheries Hokkaido University, September 1975 (Box 3, Volume 3)
    Vol. 26 No. 2, Written in Japanese and English
  - Bulletin of the Faculty of Fisheries Hokkaido University, December 1975 (Box 3, Volume 4)
    Vol. 26 No. 3, Written in Japanese and English
  - Experimental Approaches to Limnology, 1973 (Box 3, Volume 5)